Caleb W. Lovell

Bluffdale, UT 84065, USA

caleblovell1@gmail.com | +1 (262) 349-5921 | linkedin.com/in/caleblovell | www.caleblovell.dev

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-stack **web developer** with over a year of experience in front and back-end development. Broad knowledge of major web technologies and passionate about creating interactive and user-friendly design. Highly effective communicator in four languages with a bachelor's degree in political science and strategic communication.

EDUCATION

DevMountain | Lehi, Utah **02/2019 – 05/2019**

Full-Stack Web Development Immersive Bootcamp

Miami University | Oxford, Ohio 09/2013 – 05/2017

Bachelor of Arts | Overall GPA 3.57 / 4.00

Majors: Political Science, Strategic Communication

DEV SKILLS

| • | JavaScript | • | Node / Node.js | • | React Native | • | SASS |
|---|------------------|---|----------------|---|--------------|---|---------------|
| • | HTML | • | Postgres | • | Gatsby | • | ESLint |
| • | CSS | • | Docker | • | GraphQL | • | Prettier |
| • | React / React.js | • | Firebase | • | APIs | • | Git |
| • | Redux / Redux.is | • | D3 / D3.js | • | Stripe | • | Diango |

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer, Project Manager | Bright Bridge Web | Full-Time

08/2019 - Present

- Helped develop custom solutions for clients in various web and mobile technologies.
- Specialized in React.js for front-ends, Node.js and PostgresQL for back-ends, and React Native for mobile.
- Managed several projects from start to finish, ensuring team always had clear direction and tasks to complete.
- Served as lead developer on several projects, collaborating with clients and the development team to understand and implement creative solutions on a daily basis.

Web Developer | Dev Mountain Student | Full-Time

02/2019 - 06/2019

- Built nearly one hundred demo applications while learning the fundamentals of web development.
- Created two full CRUD applications with React front-ends, Node.js REST APIs, and PostgreSQL databases.
- Collaborated with a small team to create an interactive map website of all US counties that allows users to view each county's data and dynamically shade the map according to a number of user inputs.

Translator | Self-Employed | Part-Time

06/2017 - Present

- Translated hundreds of safety and technical documents between English and Spanish.
- Investigated unfamiliar technical topics to better understand the information and choose the most accurate phrasing possible.
- Served as a personal interpreter in Ecuador on a clean water humanitarian trip, explaining the technical process of filter installation to locals.

LANGUAGES

Spanish – Advanced

Portuguese – Fluent

Italian – Intermediate